PYTHON/DJANGO DEVELOPER

Python Django backend developer with 7 years of experience in web development and Fin-tech software products. My expertise lies in developing REST APIs, back-end development, data visualization, web/PDF scraping, deployment, Linux shell scripting, and ETL tools. I have extensive knowledge in Python, JavaScript, and JQuery, and have a full-stack developer background. My focus is primarily on back-end development, and I have a strong track record of delivering high-quality projects.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Programming Languages

• Python • SQL • C • C++

Front-end Technologies

HTML
 CSS
 Materialize CSS

Python Libraries

· NumPy · Pandas · SciPy · Scikit-Learn

Javascript Library

JQuery • Reactjs

Data Visualization

Plotly
 Matplotlib
 Highcharts
 Chartjs
 D3.js

Frameworks

Django
 Plotly Dash

Database

MySQLMongoDBPostgreSQLOracle

Version Control

• Git • GitHub • Bitbucket

Web Servers

ApacheNginxApache Tomcat

Operating System

• Ubuntu • Fedora • Windows • Kali Linux

Asynchronous

CeleryRedis

DevOps Tools

Docker

Programming Concepts

- · Multi-threading · Multi-Processing
- Regex, Exception Handling OOP
- · Data Handing

Data Management & Queries

- · Data Modelling/Transformation
- · Data Processing on Structured/Unstructured Data
- · Query Building/Optimization

Web Services

· HTTP · SOAP · REST · XML · JSON

AWS

- EC2 S3 ECS Secret Manager EMR
- VPC subnets

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Previous

Jul 2023 - Sept 2023

Synapse: https://synapsefi.com/

Software Engineer

- Design, build, and maintain full-stack, customer-facing features
- Work on the core infrastructure to improve Customer Experience
- Identifying and resolving performance issues and functional bugs
- Collaborate with team members on priorities and technical specification
- Identifying root causes, proposing test cases and fixes, and developing new de bugging tools while working closely with product teams
- Backend Developer in Python 3.11, PostgreSQL, Django 4.2 for BaaS product.

Previous

April 2022 - April 2023

Societe Generale: https://www.societegenerale.com/

Specialist Software Developer

In addition to my responsibilities as a Full Stack Web Developer,

I also undertook other tasks and duties.

- SonarQUbe testing on web applications
- Creating pipelines with python, SQL, SQLAlchemy to work with ETL tools
- Handled migrations of GTK Applications
- Automated migrations using jenkin scripts and Azure feed
- Backend Developer in Python 3.11/Django 4.2 for OneConsole web project.

Previous

Dec 2019 - April 2022

HTC Global Services : https://www.htcinc.com/

Python Developer

Employed as a Full Stack Developer at *Societe Generale's* Bangalore location, working on-site at the client's office.

- Full Stack Developer
- Backend Developer in Python3.1 /Django 4.2
- With SQLAlchemy and PostgreSQL Database
- Front End development in Django Material and materialize CSS
- Asynchronous task Queue using Celery and Redis
- Bug and quality checking using Pylint, Django-lint
- Security issues identification using Bandit
- Deployment using NginX.

Previous

Jan 2017 – Oct 2019

Valustat Limited: http://valustat.co/

Python Developer

Valustat Limited is a UK based company providing portfolio management solution to financial advisors. Leading a 4 member team in cochin, working on Investment Analysis Tools, which offers portfolio construction, risk assessment, strategy backtesting, and investment analysis tool.

- Backend Developer in Python/Django
- Experience with SQL and NoSQL databases
- Creating REST API's and documentation
- Building web-based analytics applications with Plotly Dash Framework
- PDF information Extraction and Visual debugging
- Modifications on the Reactis UI
- Experience in NumPy,Pandas,SciPy libraries
- Data Visualisation using Plotly, Highcharts, Chartis
- Unit testing
- Selenium testing
- AWS deployment
- Web scraping

Previous Jun 2016 - Dec 2016

Cognalys solutions: https://www.cognalys.com/

Python/Django Developer

Cognalys, Inc.is a US based company providing a multi platform service which

help application developers in verifying the mobile number in their applications using missed call technology. I was part of a 6 member team in Cochin branch, mainly working with a crowdfunding software.

It was a web application built in Python/Django, with the joint ventures of Cognalys Solutions and PPJ group.

- started my career as a Python/Django developer
- Full stack web developer with HTML,CSS,Javascript,JQuery
- Focused on Backend Development and functionalities at the frontend.
- Testing of the web application

EDUCATION

Present

Oct 2023 - May 2023

Conestoga College, Ontario, Canada

Student in Virtualization and Cloud Computing.

With a focus on Virtualisation and Cloud Computing in the IT sector, specialised in migrating physical infrastructure to cloud environments for cost savings and efficient management. I've completed a two-semester Ontario College Graduate Certificate program, gaining hands-on skills in cloud infrastructure design, workload management, business continuity, migration planning, and solution integration. (https://www.conestogac.on.ca/fulltime/virtualization-and-cloud-computing)

May 2016

Mahatma Gandhi University, Kerala, India

Bachelor's Degree

- CGPA 7/10
- Bachelor of Technology
- Computer Science

LINKS

LinkedIn

https://www.linkedin.com/in/shintojoseph1234/

GitHub

https://github.com/shintojoseph1234

Stack Overflow

https://stackoverflow.com/users/7457047/shintojoseph

PERSONAL DETAILS

Date of Birth Sex

Passport

- 8 January 1994
- Male
- Valid